Hey!
...a dark
and stormy Halloween.
Good evening and welcome to
GC-1 News live at 8:00.
Our top story tonight,
just-released polls
have incumbent
Mayor Don Mitchell, Jr.
and 28-year-old
grassroots challenger
Bella Real in
a dead heat.
Things certainly
got hot last night
in their final debate before
next Tuesday's election.
Now, my young
opponent here
wants to gut
the Gotham Renewal Program,
established by
the great Thomas Wayne.
Cutting funds
from vital projects
like our seawall,
and the safety net
for those who need it.
The Renewal Program is broken.
This city's been renewing
for 20 years.
Look where it's gotten us.
Crime has skyrocketed.
Murder and drug use
are at historic highs.
Now wait... Now hang on.
We have a masked vigilante
running the street.
Under my administration,
the Gotham PD
has dealt major blows
to organized crime
and drug trafficking.
The Salvatore Maroni case
was the biggest drug bust
in city history.
But drops and other drugs
are still rampant.
-It's gotten worse.
-I'm not saying...
I'm not saying
there isn't work to do.
But listen...
...I have a beautiful wife
and young son, okay?
And I will not rest...
Hey.
Yeah, I'm watching it now.
Why is she still tied?
But...
But I thought we were getting a
bump in the newPostpoll.
Okay, you know what?
I can't...
I can't watch this anymore.
Just call me
in the morning, okay?
...who still believes
in everything
this city can do.
We need a leader,
Mr. Mitchell,
not a cheerleader.
And someone who will
tell the people the truth.
Thursday,
October 31st.
The city streets are
crowded for the holiday.
Even with the rain.
Hidden in the chaos
is the element
waiting to strike like snakes.
But I'm there too.
Watching.
Two years of nights
have turned me
into a nocturnal animal.
I must choose
my targets carefully.
Come on!
- Give me the money.
- Okay.
- Let's go! Let's go!
- All right, all right!
It's a big city.
I can't be everywhere.
But they don't know
where I am.
Look at this guy, man.
- Boom!
- Whoo-hoo-hoo!
So good, man.
That's what I'm talking about!
Yo, let's see your hits.
That's you.
We have a signal now.
For when I'm needed.
But when that light
hits the sky,
it's not just a call.
It's a warning.
To them.
Fear...
...is a tool.
Are you
out of your mind?
Watch where you're goin',
drophead!
They think
I'm hiding in the shadows.
Come on!
But I
am the shadows.
Come on, come on.
Whoo.
-Hey, go on, man! Go!
-Get him!
-Come on, man!
-What are you doin'?
Help!
Somebody help me!
Help, help!
Where you goin', huh?
-Come on.
-Come on, man. Break it.
You can't move, huh?
Now knock his ass out.
Showtime. Showtime, man.
Come on, man.
Come on. Do it, man.
You see this guy?
The hell are you
supposed to be?
I'm vengeance.
Holy shit. It's him.
Hey, man. No, no, no!
Please don't hurt me.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Police action.
He's with me, Officer.
Are you kidding me, sir?
You're gonna let him in here?
Martinez, let him through.
Goddamn freak.
What do we know?
Detective?
Sorry, Lieutenant.
We got blunt force trauma.
Lacerations on the head.
He got hit a lot of times.
And hard.
All this blood
is from his head?
No.
Excuse me.
Most of it's from his hand.
Thumb was severed.
Killer may have taken it
as a trophy.
He was alive
when it was cut off.
Ecchymosis
around the wound.
Security detail downstairs
said the family was out
trick-or-treatin'.
The mayor was up here alone.
Killer may have come
through the skylight.
You said
there was a card.
Yeah.
"From your
secret friend. Whoo?
Haven't a clue?
Let's play a game,
just me and you.
What does a liar do
when he's dead?"
There's a cipher too.
Any of this
mean anything to you?
What's going on here?
I asked him to come, Pete.
This is a crime scene.
It's Mitchell, for chrissakes!
I got the press downstairs.
You know, I cut you
a lot of slack, Jim,
'cause we got history.
But this is way over the line.
Wait.
-He's involved in this?
-No, he's not involved.
How do you know?
He's a goddamn vigilante!
He could be a suspect!
What are you doin' to me?
We used to be partners.
I'm just trying
to find the connection, Pete.
He lies still.
Excuse me?
The riddle.
What does a liar do
when he's dead?
He lies still.
Oh, Jesus.
This must be your favorite
night of the year, huh, pal?
Happy fuckin' Halloween.
Excuse me,
Commissioner.
They're ready
for your statement.
I want him outta here.
Now!
Come on.
Yeah.
The kid found him.
Was there anyone else
in the house when you arrived?
We really gotta go, man.
Tonight,
a son lost a father.
A wife lost a husband.
And I lost a friend.
Mayor Mitchell was a fighter
for the city,
and I will not rest
until his killer is found.
This was
a truly senseless crime,
and we are
actively pursuing
every investigative lead
we have
in order to identify
the perpetrator
and hunt him down.
I've spoken to the governor...
I wish I could say
I'm making a difference,
but I don't know.
Murder, robberies,
assault.
Two years later,
they're all up.
And now this.
The city's eating itself.
Maybe it's beyond saving.
But I have to try.
Push myself.
These nights all roll
together in a rush,
behind the mask.
Sometimes in the morning,
I have to force myself
to remember
everything that happened.
Unbelievable breaking
news
this hour, everyone.
Again, four-term incumbentGotham
Mayor Don Mitchell, Jr.
was found murdered last night
inside his home
in the exclusive
Crest Hill district.
Exact
details of the crime
still have not
been released,
but a citywide manhunt
is already underway
as police and FBI search
for the brazen killer.
And this certainly
is not the first time
Gotham has been rocked
by the murder
of a political figure.
In fact,
in an eerie coincidence,
it was 20 years
ago this week
that celebrated
billionaire philanthropist
Dr. Thomas Wayne
and his wife Martha
were slain during Wayne's
own mayoral campaign.
It was a shocking crime
that remains unsolved
to this day.
Don Mitchell, Jr.'s
political career
was especially notable
for his tough war on drugs
when he and city police
launched a major
sting operation
resulting in the arrest
of notorious mafia crime
figure Salvatore Maroni,
with what, to this day,
remains the biggest drug bust
in GCPD history.
I assume you heard about this.
Yeah.
Oh, I see.
All this
blood is from his head?
Dear God.
There's a cipher too.
Any of this
mean anything to you?
The killer left this
for the Batman?
I asked
him to come, Pete.
Apparently.
You're becoming
quite a celebrity.
Why is he writing to you?
It's Mitchell,
for chrissakes!
I don't know yet.
I got the press
downstairs.
Have a shower.
Our accounting friends
at Wayne Enterprises
are coming for breakfast.
Here? Why?
Because I couldn't get you
to go there.
-I haven't got time for this.
-It's getting serious, Bruce.
If this continues,
it won't be long
before you've nothing left.
I don't care about that.
Any of that.
You don't care
about your family's legacy?
What I'm doing
is my family's legacy.
If I can't change things here,
if I can't have an effect,
then I don't care
what happens to me.
That's what I'm afraid of.
Alfred, stop.
You're not my father.
I'm well aware.
We really gotta go, man.
Some fresh berries there.
What are you doing?
Just reminiscing about my days
in the Circus.
This is
actually quite elusive.
Where'd you get those O's?
"He lies still"
is only a partial key.
It only gives us
H, E, L, I, S, and T.
So, I'm looking for
any double symbols to start,
trying letters,
see where it leads.
That's interesting.
Mr. Pennyworth?
Yes, Dory?
The accountants are here.
See them in, please, Dory.
What if
it's not a partial key?
What do you mean?
What if this is the whole key?
Ignore the symbols
we don't have letters for.
Use only the letters
from "He lies still"
-and leave the rest...
-Blank. Yeah, I understand.
But that would leave
most of the cipher unsolved.
I don't see
how that's gonna...
Oh.
Damn.
Yeah, he's got a car.
Guess it's good
to be the mayor.
Where to even start?
You sure this isn't a leap?
"Drive" could mean anything.
You don't trust me?
You mean like you trust me?
It's been two years now,
and I don't even know
who you are, man.
There.
What are we looking for?
A USB port.
USB?
What?
"Thumb" drive.
Jesus.
It's encrypted.
Try this.
Oh, this guy's hilarious.
Oh, well, well, well.
So much for family values.
Who is she?
No idea.
But that's the Penguin,
Carmine Falcone's right hand.
I know who he is.
What was that?
Shit, shit, shit! The drive.
It sent out the photos
from my account.
Gotham Post, Gazette,
GC-1, all of them.
Jesus.
I'm gonna catch hell for this.
Pete's gonna bust a gasket.
"He lies still."
About her?
Maybe.
That's the Iceberg Lounge.
It's under the Shoreline Lofts
where Falcone was holed up.
Never get in there
without a warrant.
Yeah.
Know who I am?
Yeah. I got an idea.
I want to see the Penguin.
I don't know what
you're talking about, pal.
What's the problem?
Says he wants
to see the Penguin.
Penguin?
There's no Penguin here.
That's what
I tried to tell him.
Get out of here, freak.
You hear me?
Or that little suit's
gonna get all full of blood.
Mine or yours?
Get him!
I saw that whole thing.
He's over there!
What is your problem?
Yo!
Hey! Put the bat down,
or I'll blow your head off!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Take it easy, sweetheart.
You looking for me?
I see you met the twins.
Boy, you're everything
they say, ain't ya?
I guess we both are.
How you doing?
I'm Oz.
Who is she?
I really don't know, chief.
I might have been coming out
at the same time,
but I wasn't rolling
with them.
It's okay, baby.
Mr. Vengeance here,
he don't bite. Come on.
Thank you, honey.
Here you go, champ.
I wanna know who she is,
and what she has to do
with this murder.
-Whose murder?
-The mayor's.
Is that the mayor?
Oh, shit, it is. Look at that.
Don't make me hurt you.
You better watch it.
You know my reputation?
Yeah, I do. Do you?
Look...
I'm just the proprietor, okay?
I mean, what people do here
ain't got nothing to do
with me.
Tell you one thing.
Whoever she is,
she's one hot chick.
Why don't you ask
Mitchell's wife?
Maybe she knows.
What? Too soon?
You let me know if there's
anything else I can do.
Taxi!
Hey, it's me.
Baby, what's wrong?
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Slow down,
slow down. I can't...
On the news?
Okay. No. No, stay there.
Wait for me, okay?
Wait for me,
I'm on my way home.
Listen, baby,
we're gonna get the hell
out of here, okay? I promise.
If we have to leave earlier,
we'll leave tonight.
Uh...
God damn it.
...photos
of murdered mayor,
Don Mitchell, Jr. with
a younger mystery woman.
In a shocking
development,
the police believe
the photos themselves...
Now they urge her
to contact the GCPD...
You're pretty good at that.
Hey! Give me that.
"Kosolov, Annika."
He hurt her?
That's why you killed him?
What? Oh, please.
Just give me the goddamn...
Listen, honey,
you got the wrong idea, okay?
I didn't kill anybody.
I'm here for my friend.
She's trying to get
the hell out of here,
and this son of a bitch
stole her passport.
What does she know?
Whatever it is,
it's got her so spooked
she won't even tell me.
She did seem upset.
Back at your place.
Let's go talk to her.
Anni!
Baby!
It's gonna
be cool this evening.
It's gonna be down
into the 40s.
More
breaking news this hour,
as the city is rocked by a
second high-profile murder
in as many nights.
And this time, the killer
has come forward
to claim credit online...
Jesus, what are they
gonna do to her?
She's just a kid.
- Shit, they took my phone.
- -His victim,
longtime head
of the Gotham City PD,
Commissioner Pete Savage,
was found dead
earlier tonight
inside the Police
Athletic League facilities
in the Tricorner area.
The killer posted
the following message
on social media,
and we have to warn you, the
video is very disturbing.
Hello, people of Gotham.
This is the
Riddler speaking.
On Halloween night,
I killed your mayor
because he was not
who he pretended to be.
But I am not done.
Here is another...
...who will soon
be losing face.
I will kill again,
and again, and again
until our day of judgment
when the truth about our city
will finally
be unmasked.
Goodbye!
Commissioner Savage
served
a distinguished 30-year
career on the GCPD...
Holy shit,
I seen that guy, too.
At the club.
The Iceberg Lounge?
44 Below.
What is that?
The club within the club.
The real club.
It's a mob hangout.
Is that where you work?
Selina?
No, I just work
the bar upstairs.
But I see 'em come in.
Who?
A lot of guys
that shouldn't be there,
I can tell you that.
Your basic
upstanding citizen types.
You're gonna help me on this.
For your friend.
You got a lot of cats.
I have a thing about strays.
You're not safe here.
I can take care of myself.
Two
public figures
now dead in just
the last two nights,
and only days
before the election.
Police and city officials
are left searching
for a killer
and hoping to find him
before he kills again.
He waited for him at the gym.
Pete always liked
to work out late at night,
when no one else was around.
There's a needle mark
on his neck.
Injected him with arsenic.
Rat poison.
Yeah.
That seems to be
his theme here.
Look at this thing.
It's a maze.
What kind of demented
son of a bitch
does this to a person?
More symbols.
It's another cipher.
He blasted these out
after his message went viral.
Bastard murders you
and your reputation.
That guy pushes drops.
On the east end.
I don't get it.
Why would Pete get involved
in something like this?
Looks like he got greedy.
You kidding me?
After everything we did
to take down the Maronis?
We busted
their entire operation,
then he caves
to some lowlife dealer?
Maybe he's not
who you thought.
You make it sound
like he had it coming.
He was a cop.
Crossed a line.
"I'm mad about you.
Want to know my name?
Just look inside and see."
"Follow the maze
until you find the rat.
Bring him into the light,
and you'll find where I'm at."
The hell is that?
"Bring him into the light"?
"Find the rat"?
I don't know.
Lieutenant.
They're coming back.
We got
to get out of here.
Come on.
Ow.
I don't know
about these things.
I need to see in there,
this hunting ground.
Hey, why am I starting to feel
like a fish on a hook?
I'm just looking for Annika.
Boy, you're a real sweetheart.
You really don't care
what happens to me
in there tonight, do you?
Look at me.
Looks good. Here.
I got you. Can you hear me?
Yeah.
Hey, where you goin'?
Hospitality.
That's
one of the guys
I got into it with
the other night.
Looks like I
broke his nose.
"Kenzie, William."
He's an off-duty cop.
Are you sure no one can see
these things in my eyes?
Don't worry. I'm watching you.
Don't look away.
I need time to make IDs.
Great.
These guys
have a little problem
with eye contact, don't they?
Feels good, doesn't it?
Yeah, baby.
Feels real good.
Jesus,
I hate dropheads.
Really?
'Cause when I first saw you,
it looked like you were
dealing for Penguin.
You don't know
what you're talking about.
Can we not...
Can we not do this right now?
Wait. Who was that?
Oh, I saw him.
Look back.
If I look back, it's gonna be
a whole can of worms.
I need to see his face.
Jesus.
That's the DA.
Gil Colson.
And he's coming over.
You happy?
Talk to him.
Hey. How you doing?
-Hi.
-I'm Gil.
-Hey, aren't you the DA?
-Yeah.
Wow.
I've seen you on TV.
Is that right?
I haven't seen you
around here before.
It's a hell of a time
to be the new girl
'cause people
are all a little on edge.
Oh, honey,
I live on the edge.
Is that right?
I
like that.
Do you want to come over?
Sure.
- This is Travis.
- Hey.
You wanna take a seat
over there?
- Richie, Glen.
- Hey.
That's half the DA's office.
You know
Carla here, huh?
-Hi.
-That's Cheri. Don't mind her,
she's just taking a break.
Drowning our sorrows.
You want a drop?
Uh, no, I'm good.
But you enjoy.
Hope you don't mind.
I got a lot on
my shoulders
with that psycho
running around.
He's wasted.
No shit.
I
like this girl.
Oh, hey, I like you, too!
I mean, this Riddler,
he's going after the most
powerful people in the city.
He knows so much.
He doesn't
know shit, man.
What are you
talking about?
Yeah, he does!
What about that rat...
Hey, hey,
Gil, come on.
Hey. The rat. -Think
maybe you had
-a little too much. Slow down.
-Ask him about the rat.
Hey,
what's this about a rat?
I mean,
there was a rat.
We had an informant.
We had big-time information
on Salvatore Maroni.
That's how we got him out of
the drops business.
He's talking about
the Maroni case.
But if this guy knows,
it's gonna come out.
And when it does,
this whole city's
gonna come apart.
Okay, I don't wanna hear this.
This is
the kind of pillow talk
that got that Russian girl
disappeared.
What do you know about that?
- Does anybody want a drink?
- I want a drink.
Keep him talking.
-Wait, where are you going?
-She knows Annika.
No, stay on the DA.
I told you
I'm looking for my friend.
Where's Annika?
Out of my face.
I don't know you.
Yeah, but you know her.
Who took her?
What have you heard?
Is she okay?
Jesus Christ,
keep your voice down.
What, you got
a death wish?
Hey,
what's the problem, ladies?
There's no problem.
It's just girl talk.
Let's keep it festive
down here, all right?
Sure thing, Oz.
Hey.
Been a long time
since I seen you down here.
How you been?
Yeah, I've been okay.
I was just, um...
I was just headed back
upstairs.
Mm. Well,
don't be a stranger.
-You know Carmine Falcone.
-I told you it's a mob spot.
You didn't tell me you had
a relationship with him.
I don't have a relationship
with him, okay?
Well, that's not
what it looked like.
-Forget it.
-Wait, what are you doing?
Listen,
I can't do this anymore.
No! No!
Taxi!
Hey!
I lost you in there.
Yeah, I gotta go.
Oh, you need a ride?
That's me right there.
Taxi!
I'm good.
I hope, uh...
I'll see you around.
Just hold still.
What do you know
about a confidential informant
in the Maroni case?
Yeah, sure, there was.
That's the rat
we're looking for.
Somehow
Riddler knows who he is.
If we find the rat,
maybe it'll lead us to him.
Where are you getting this?
I have a source
who spoke to the DA tonight.
Gil's very nervous.
I think the killer's targeting
people close to that case.
I worked that case.
-Riddler's not after you.
-How do you know?
You're not corrupt.
Colson's dirty?
Maybe I, uh...
I go after him. Lean on him
to give up the rat.
It's too dangerous.
They made a secret deal
with this guy.
Who knows how many people
it touches.
Politicians. Police.
The courts.
It could tear
the whole city apart.
Jesus,
this is a powder keg.
And Riddler's the match.
You know Carmine Falcone.
I told you
it's a mob spot.
You didn't tell me you
had a relationship with him.
I don't have
a relationship...
You didn't tell me you
had a relationship with him.
I don't have
a relationship with him.
Okay?
You know
Carmine Falcone.
I told you
it's a mob spot.
You didn't tell me you
had a relationship with him.
I don't have a relationship with him.
Okay?
Pretty.
She a new friend of yours?
I'm not so sure.
Looks like you upset her.
Shall I take this
as a good sign?
-What?
-Your attire.
Is Bruce Wayne
making an actual appearance?
There's a public memorial
for Mayor Mitchell.
Serial killers like to follow
reactions to their crimes.
Riddler might not
be able to resist.
Oh, that reminds me.
I've taken the liberty
of doing a little work
on this latest cipher.
The one from the rat maze.
I'm afraid his Spanish
is not perfect,
but I'm fairly certain
this translates to,
"You areEl Rata Alada."
Rata Alada?
"Rat with wings"?
It's slang for "pigeon."
Does that mean anything
to you?
Yeah.
A stool pigeon.
-Where are your cufflinks?
-I couldn't find them.
Well, you can't
go out like that.
Alfred, I don't want
your cufflinks.
You have to keep up
appearances.
You're still a Wayne.
And what about you?
Are you a Wayne?
Your father gave them to me.
No more lies! No more lies!
Mr. Wayne. All right.
All right, you're going
straight down there.
Is that Bruce Wayne?
Mr. Wayne!
Mr. Wayne! Mr. Wayne!
Hold it.
You good, fellas?
Good.
We're good, Mr. Falcone.
Sir?
Hey!
Give us a wide berth here,
would you, slick?
Hey, watch it, fellas.
You got the prince
of the city there.
Some event, huh?
Brought out the one guy
in the city
more reclusive than me.
Thought you'd never leave
the Shoreline.
Aren't you afraid
someone'll take a shot at you?
Why? 'Cause your father
ain't around?
Oz, you know Bruce Wayne?
Wow, is that right?
His father saved my life.
I got shot in the chest.
Right here.
I couldn't go to no hospital,
so we showed up
on his doorstep.
Operated right
on the dining room table.
Kid here,
he saw the whole thing,
up on the stairs looking down.
I remember your face.
You don't think that meant
something, he did that?
It meant he took
the Hippocratic oath.
"Hippocratic oath."
That's good.
Excuse me.
Yes.
Ladies and gentlemen,
thank you all for coming
to today's memorial
for our beloved mayor,
Don Mitchell, Jr.
Our program
will begin shortly.
As a reminder,
the family asked
that those wishing to honor
the mayor's memory
consider a donation
to the cause
most dear to his heart...
...the Gotham
Renewal Fund,
our city's safety net.
What good's a safety net
doesn't catch anybody?
Didn't help my daughter
when she needed it,
I can tell you that.
The guy was just another
rich scum-sucker.
He got what he deserved.
Know what I mean?
Hey, don't I know you?
Bruce Wayne.
Why haven't
you called me back?
I'm sorry?
I'm Bella Real.
I'm running for mayor.
I wouldn't be bothering
you here,
but your people keep
telling me you're unavailable.
Will you walk with me?
Mr. Wayne.
You know, you really could be
doing more for this city.
Your family
has a history of philanthropy,
but as far as I can tell,
you're not doing anything.
If I'm elected,
I want to change that.
Thank you.
My God.
I'm gonna go pay my respects.
Will you wait for me?
I want to continue this.
Excuse me.
I'm so sorry for your loss.
Thank you.
Excuse me, chief.
Can I talk to you?
Gil Colson is missing.
What?
He hasn't been heard from
since last night.
Christ, not again.
Hey. Mr. Wayne.
You got people
looking for him, Jim?
Sent a couple guys
to his house. Nothing.
What'd his wife say?
She hadn't
heard from him.
Get out of the car!
Get out of the car
and show your hands!
Get out!
Get 'em up!
Get out! Show 'em!
Christ, it's Colson.
There's a bomb
around his neck!
Let's clear
this place out now!
We've got to get
this place cleared out!
Hey, guys, guys.
Here we go.
We don't know
if he's in on it.
What's he looking at?
Holy shit.
Are you kidding me?
What the hell is he doing?
Gordon!
Your guy's gonna get himself
killed in there.
Please.
- He made me do it.
- I'm so sorry.
He told me if I didn't do
exactly what he said,
he'd kill me.
I'm so sorry.
Looks like a combination lock.
Can't we just cut it off?
Not if you want
to keep your head.
You came.
Who are you?
Me?
I'm nobody.
I'm just an instrument,
here to unmask the truth
about this cesspool
we call a city.
"Unmask"?
Yes.
Let's do it
together, okay?
I've been trying to reach you.
You're part of this, too.
How am I a part of this?
You'll see.
Hey, Chief. You
better take a look at this.
Say
hello to my followers.
We're live.
They're here to watch
our little trial.
At the moment,
the man across
from you, Mr. Colson,
is dead.
Jesus, can we
get somebody out here?
-This psycho's gonna kill me!
-But wait a minute...
Shut up!
You deserve to be dead
after what you did!
You hear me?
Okay.
I'm giving you a chance.
No one ever gave
me a chance.
Now,
ever since I was a child,
I've always loved
little puzzles.
For me, they
are a retreat
from the horrors of our world.
Maybe they can bring
some comfort to you too,
Mr. Colson.
You want me to do puzzles?
Three riddles
in two minutes.
You give me the answers,
and I'll give you
the code for the lock.
-Do you understand?
-Yeah.
Okay, okay. So I just...
You want me to...
Riddle number one...
"It can be cruel,
poetic, or blind,
"but when it's denied, it's
violence you may find."
Wait, wait, wait!
Can you repeat that?
"Cruel"? "Poetic"?
-"Justice."
-Huh?
The answer's "justice."
-Justice?
-Yes!
-Oh, God.
-Justice!
And you
were supposed to be
an arm of justice
in this city,
along with the late mayor
and police commissioner,
were you not, Mr. Colson?
Of course, of course.
-Of course.
-Riddle number two.
"If you are justice,
please do not lie.
"What is the price
for your blind eye?"
- "The price"?
- "Bribes."
Oh, God. "Bribes"?
He's asking you
how much it cost
for you to turn your back.
Fifty-eight seconds!
-How much?
-Nothing!
- How much?
- Ten grand. Ten Gs a month.
I get a monthly payment
just not to prosecute
certain cases.
-What cases?
-He didn't ask me that!
Come on! Ten grand.
That's my answer.
It's ten grand!
Okay. Okay. Okay.
Don't lose your head,
Mr. Colson.
Just one more to go
before your time runs out.
Last riddle.
"Since
your justice is so select,
please tell us which vermin
you're paid to protect."
- "Which vermin"?
- The rat.
The informant you all protect
from
the Salvatore Maroni case.
-How do you know about that?
-What's his name?
-Twenty seconds.
-No.
-He's gonna kill you.
-I'm a dead man either way.
You're talking
to a dead man, okay?
If I go out this way,
it's just me.
But if I give over that name,
I have family, people I love.
-He'll kill them, too.
-Who will?
-People are watching.
-What people?
It's so much bigger
than you could ever imagine.
It's the whole system!
Five! Four!
-Oh, God, have mercy on
me... -Three!
Goodbye!
Who do you
think he is under there?
- Take it easy.
- I want to see.
What is that thing?
Leather?
What's he got
on his eyes?
Who cares?
I want to see his face.
-We are we doing here?
-Let's just take it off...
Hey!
Hey! Hey! Hey!
Hey! Hey!
Relax, God damn it!
You're protecting
this guy, Jim?
He interfered in an active
hostage situation.
Colson's blood
is on his hands.
Maybe it's on yours.
What'd you say?
He would rather die than talk.
What was he afraid of?
You?
You son of a bitch.
You have any idea what kind
of trouble you're in?
You could be
an accessory to murder.
Why are we
playing games...
Get him! Come on!
Back off! Back off!
Great, now I got you
on assaulting an officer!
You got me
on assaulting three.
Hey!
What's the matter with you?
This isn't the way to do this!
You too now?
Let me handle this, Chief.
Just give me a minute.
You're gonna put yourself
on the line
for this scumbag, Jim?
Just give me a minute.
I'll get him to cooperate.
Okay, give him the room.
Two minutes.
You listen to me.
We gotta get you out of here.
That would put
a lot of heat on you.
Well, you punched me
in the face.
Take this key.
Through that door.
Hallway to the stairs
that go to the roof.
Hey, what the hell
is going on here?
Hey, hey, hey,
what's going on?
Who's the mustache
with the broken nose?
That's Kenzie. Narcotics.
He's one of the guys
I got into it with
at the Iceberg Lounge.
What are you saying?
Kenzie moonlights
for the Penguin?
Or he moonlights as a cop.
- Jesus Christ!
- Go!
Somebody stop him!
- There he is!
- Freeze!
Could have at least
pulled that punch, man.
I did.
Bock put out an APB on you.
You really think
he's in on this?
I don't trust any of 'em.
Do you?
I only trust you.
What's a narcotics cop doing
with Falcone's right-hand man?
Colson said,
"Cops protect the rat."
Maybe Kenzie's part of it.
You think Penguin's the rat?
His club caters to the mob.
Maroni
practically lived there.
Penguin would have been
privy to a lot of dirt.
DA was a regular, too.
Maybe Penguin
got himself into a jam
and working a deal
was his only way out.
-TheRata Alada.
-The what?
Riddler's latest.
The cipher in the maze.
It means "a rat with wings."
Like a stool pigeon.
A penguin's got wings, too.
Time for me to have
another conversation with him.
What about the Riddler?
He's gonna kill again.
It's all connected.
Like it or not,
it's his game now.
You want to find Riddler,
we gotta find that rat.
Kenzie and the twins,
coming your way.
There's Penguin.
I wonder
what's in the bags.
You want to move in?
Let's follow.
They stopped
at Waterfront Street.
The recycling plant.
I'm here.
- How you doing?
- Yeah, good. How are you?
Good, good.
Let's get in
out of this deluge.
It's a drug lab. Drops.
This is a buy.
Looks like
they got Maroni's operation
up and running again.
Or they never
shut it down at all.
What
are you saying?
The biggest drug bust
in GCPD history was a fraud?
This just got complicated.
What do you mean?
Hey! What happened?
You all right?
Dangerous crowd
you're stealing from.
Jesus.
Is this how
you get your kicks, hon?
Sneaking up on girls
in the dark?
Is that why
you work in the club?
It was all just a score?
You know, I would love
to sit and go over
every gory detail
with you, bat boy,
but, uh, those assholes
are coming back.
Jesus!
Hey, Vengeance!
You think you can come
after my money, huh?
Kenzie! Get the money!
Hey! What the...
Whoa!
Come on! Come on!
This guy's crazy!
Come on! Hey!
Move!
Get out of the way!
Come on!
I got you!
Take that,
you friggin' psycho!
I got you!
What the hell is this?
Good cop, batshit cop?
-Who's the Riddler?
-Riddler? How should I know?
Let's make it
easy for you, Oz.
Cops caught you
doing something.
They were gonna
shut you down, put you away.
So you gave up a bigger fish
to save your ass.
You ratted out
Salvatore Maroni.
His drops operation.
But the cops,
the city officials,
the mayor, the DA,
they got greedy, right?
Wasn't enough,
a big career-making bust.
They wanted to take over
the drops business too,
but they needed a minor league
mope like you to run it.
You don't just work
for Carmine Falcone.
You work for them, too.
What are you, crazy?
That why
you killed the girl?
I didn't kill no girl!
We know she worked for you
at the 44 Below.
But she got too close, right?
Found out from Mitchell
that you were the rat,
so you killed her.
But somehow
Riddler found out, too.
He knows so much about you.
-You must know about him.
-Who is he?
Boy, you guys are a hell
of a duet here.
Why don't you start
harmonizing?
There's only one problem with
your little scenario, okay?
I ain't no rat!
You got any idea what
Carmine Falcone would do to me
if he heard this kind of talk?
Oh, you don't wanna talk
about rats, huh?
Maybe we can talk about
what they did
to my partner's face.
Holy God, what are you
showing me here?
-This was around his head!
-Come on!
Open your eyes!
Are youEl Rata Alada?
El Rata Alada?
Yeah,
a "rat with wings."
A stool pigeon.
That's not you?
The symbols in the maze,
right here.
It says you
areEl Rata Alada.
"You areEl Rata"?
It says that?
Why, you got something
to tell us?
Yeah!
It's, like, the worst Spanish
I ever heard.
-What?
-It's"La."
"La" rata.
What, is this Riddler stupid
or something?
Jesus! Look at you two.
World's greatest detectives!
Am I the only here
knows the difference
between"el"and"la"?
Jesus!
No habla espanol,fellas?
Do me a favor, shithead,
shut up!
You think he made a mistake?
He doesn't made mistakes.
A rat with wings?
You know what
that sounds like to me?
A friggin' bat! Huh?
You ever think of that?
"You areEl Rata."
"You"...
"are"...
"El."
Maybe it was a mistake.
Maybe he isn't as smart as...
Wait.
Is that him?
Holy shit.
What the hell does that mean?
Is he or isn't he?
"I grew up from a seed,
tough as a weed...
But in a mansion,
in a slum...
I'll never know
where I come from.
Do you know what I am?"
Any idea?
Yeah.
It's an orphan.
A mansion in a slum.
He's talking about
the old orphanage.
The one that burned down?
It was part of
the Wayne estate.
They donated it
after they built the tower.
Let's go.
You guys realize
I'm still here, right?
You gonna untie me?
How the hell am I supposed
to get out of here?
Hey!
You goddamn sons of bitches!
No guns.
Yeah, man.
That's your thing.
What's that?
Hey! Hey!
Dropheads.
What the hell is that?
Thank
you. Thank you so much.
Wasn't that beautiful?
Thank you all.
Thank you, uh...
Thank you for
coming today.
I believe in Gotham.
I believe in its promise.
But too many have been
left behind for too long,
and that's why I'm here today.
To announce, not only
my candidacy for mayor,
but also the creation
of the Gotham Renewal Fund.
Win or lose,
the Wayne Foundation pledges
a one billion dollar donation
to start a charitable
endowment for public works.
I want to bypass
political gridlock,
and get money
to people and projects
who need it now,
like these children behind me.
"Sins of the father."
Renewal is about growth.
It is about planting seeds
and renewing
Gotham's promise.
Shall be visited upon the son.
Jesus. His next victim
is Bruce Wayne.
Hey!
-Hello?
-Dory!
I need to speak to Alfred!
-Oh, Mr. Wayne...
-Listen to me!
Something terrible
is gonna happen!
I'm afraid
it already has, sir.
About an hour ago.
I'm so sorry.
I've been trying to reach you.
The package
was intended for you.
It was a C-4 explosive
sent in a mailer.
We found this too.
We've sedated him.
We just have to hope
he stabilizes.
You should go home, Mr. Wayne.
Get some sleep.
Is there anyone else
to notify?
Next of kin?
No.
It's just me.
Selina?
Can you see me?
-Yeah, I can see you.
-I need to talk to you.
Where can we go?
Cat burglar
pulling another score?
What?
Wasn't sure I'd see you again.
Yeah, well,
things were getting
a little hot for me, so...
How could they do that to her?
That piece of shit cop,
Kenzie.
Her body was in his car.
I'm gonna find him
and I'm gonna make him pay.
-You gonna help me?
-Help you?
Yeah. I thought
you were "Vengeance."
Your friend got involved
with the wrong people.
She didn't know any better.
Maybe you should have
explained it to her.
What the hell
is that supposed to mean?
It means your choices
have consequences.
Jesus Christ. "Choices"?
You know,
whoever the hell you are,
you obviously grew up rich.
-Was it worth it?
-What?
Compromising yourself
for money?
What did you have to do
to set up that score?
How close did you have to get
to Penguin? To Falcone?
You don't know what the hell
you're talking about.
-Falcone owes me that money.
-He owes you?
-Yeah, and a lot more.
-Oh, really? Why's that?
You know what?
I can't even talk to you.
No! I want to know
why a guy like Falcone
would owe you anything.
Because he's my father!
My mother worked
at the 44 Below.
Just like Anni.
She used to take me there
when I was a little girl.
To the club?
Yeah.
I hid out in the dressing room
while she worked.
Used to see him there.
He scared the shit out of me.
And I could never understand
why he looked at me
the way he did.
Then one night,
my mother told me who he was.
When I was seven,
my mother was murdered.
Strangled.
Never found out who.
Probably some creep
from the club.
Anyway, social services
came to take me away,
and he didn't say a thing.
Couldn't even look at me.
He owes me that money.
I'm sorry.
For what I said.
Ah, it's all right.
You assume the worst
in people.
Which, well...
maybe we're not
so different after all.
Who are you under there?
What are you hiding?
Are you just...
hideously scarred?
Yeah.
Listen to me.
If we don't stand up
for Annika, no one will.
All anyone cares about
in this place
are these white,
privileged assholes.
The mayor,
the commissioner, the DA.
Now Thomas and Bruce Wayne.
I mean, as far
as I'm concerned,
that psycho's right
to go after these creeps.
I think you'd be on his side.
What do you mean,
"Thomas and Bruce Wayne"?
What, do you live in a cave?
The Riddler's latest.
It's all about the Waynes.
Listen, if I can find
that dickbag Kenzie,
will you help me?
Please.
Come on, Vengeance.
Just don't make any moves
without me, understand?
It's a little more dangerous
than you know...
I told you, baby.
I can take care of myself.
I'm Thomas Wayne,
and I approve this message.
From a very young age,
my family, Martha's family,
the Arkhams,
instilled in
both of us
that giving back
is not just an obligation,
it's a passion.
That is our
family's legacy.
The
Waynes and the Arkhams.
Gotham's founding
families.
But what is their real legacy?
Twenty years ago,
one reporter set out
to uncover the
dark truth.
He found
shocking family secrets.
How, when Martha
was just a child,
her mother brutally
murdered her father,
then committed
suicide...
...and how the Arkhams
used their power and
money to cover it up.
How Martha herself
was in and out of
institutions for years,
and they didn't want
anyone to know.
Thomas Wayne tried to
force this crusading reporter
into a hush-money agreement
to save his mayoral campaign.
But when
the reporter refused,
Wayne turned to
longtime secret associate
Carmine Falcone,
and had him murdered!
The Waynes and
the Arkhams,
Gotham's legacy
of lies and murder.
I hopeyou're
listening, Bruce Wayne.
This is your legacy too.
And Gotham needs you to answer
for the
sins of your father.
Goodbye.
Do you know who I am?
You're Bruce Wayne.
I wanna see Carmine Falcone.
See?
Who is this guy
who invented the ball, right?
Must have made a fortune.
If you think about it,
the concept of it, right?
Briscoe, do you know
how much this sweater cost?
No, boss.
$1,183.
You know
why communism failed, right?
No, boss.
Austerity.
All right. All right.
Look at that. Perfect.
It's never gonna be
that good again.
Hey, Johnny Slick.
What are you doing here?
Give us a moment here, fellas.
Come on.
See ya, champ.
Come on, sweetheart.
Have a seat.
I thought
I might hear from you.
This, uh, Riddler
son of a bitch is really
stirring things up, huh?
-Is it true?
-What?
That reporter business?
What do you want
to know here, kid?
Did you kill him?
For my father?
Look, your father
was in trouble.
This reporter had some dirt.
Some very
personal stuff
about your mother,
her family history.
You know, everybody's got
their dirty laundry,
that's just how it is.
But he didn't want
none of it coming out,
not right before the election.
And your father
tried to pay the guy off,
but he wasn't going for it.
So...
he came to me.
Well, I never seen him
like that.
He said, "Carmine,
"I want you to put
the fear of God in this guy."
And when fear isn't enough...
Oof. Hmm.
Your father wanted me
to handle it, so I did.
I handled it.
I know.
You thought your father
was a Boy Scout.
But you'd be surprised
what even a good man like him
is capable of
in the right situation.
Do me a favor.
Don't lose any sleep over it.
This reporter
was a lowlife.
He was on Maroni's payroll.
-Maroni?
-Oh, yeah.
He could never stand
your father and I had history.
And... And after what happened
with that reporter,
Maroni was worried
that your father
would be in my pocket
forever.
He would have done anything
to keep him
from becoming mayor.
You understand?
Are you saying
Salvatore Maroni
got my father killed?
Do I know it for a fact?
I'm just saying,
it sure looked that way to me.
This is what you wanted, huh?
This little conversation here?
It's been
a long time coming, huh?
I mean,
you ain't a kid no more.
You lied to me...
my whole life.
I spoke to Carmine Falcone.
He told me what he did
for my father.
About Salvatore Maroni.
He told you
Salvatore Maroni...
Had my father killed.
Why didn't you tell me
all this?
All these years
I've spent fighting for him,
believing that he was
a good man.
He was a good man.
You listen to me.
Your father was a good man.
-He made a mistake.
-A "mistake."
He had a man killed.
Why?
To protect his family image?
His political aspirations?
It wasn't to protect
the family image,
and he didn't have
anyone killed.
He was protecting your mother.
He didn't care about his image
or the campaign, any of that.
He cared about her
and you,
and in a moment of weakness,
he turned to Falcone.
But he never thought Falcone
would kill that man.
Your father should have known
that Falcone would do anything
to finally have something
on him that he could use.
That's who Falcone is.
And that was
your father's mistake.
But when Falcone
told him what he'd done,
your father was distraught.
He told Falcone
he was going to the police,
that he would confess
everything.
And that night,
your father and your mother
were killed.
It was Falcone?
Oh, I wish I knew for sure.
Or maybe it was some
random thug on the street
who needed money, got scared,
and pulled the trigger
too fast.
If you don't think
I've spent every day
searching for that answer...
It was my job to protect them.
Do you understand?
I know you always
blamed yourself.
You were only a boy, Bruce.
I could see the fear
in your eyes,
but I didn't know how to help.
I could teach you
how to fight,
but I wasn't equipped
to take care of you.
You needed a father.
And all you had was me.
I'm sorry.
Don't be sorry, Alfred.
God.
I never thought
I'd feel fear like that again.
I thought
I'd mastered all that.
I mean,
I'm not afraid to die.
I realize now
there's something
I haven't got past.
This fear...
of ever going through
any of that again.
Of losing somebody
I care about.
Hey.
I saw the signal.
That's not you?
I thought it was you.
-I found him!
-I see that.
He had my shit and my phone.
She left a message
the night they took her.
-She called me...
-Gordon! Help me out, man!
She got my gun!
-Shut up!
-Put the gun down.
I'm telling you, God damn it!
She called me!
Here. Listen.
Hey! Get back here!
Where you going?
Come back here!
Hey, hey,
what are you doing, Kenzie?
You're scaring her.
I'm...
I'm sorry, Mr. Falcone.
Please, please, please.
Please, don't hurt me, please.
Hey, don't be scared.
Come here.
Now let me ask you again.
- What did Mitchell tell you?
- No, nothing. He...
Don liked to talk.
I know that.
Especially to pretty girls
like you.
That's why I made him
take your passport,
until we could have
this little conversation.
All I want to do
is get out of here, okay?
You'll never hear from me
again, nobody will.
Please, please...
We're gonna get you
out of here, I promise.
But first, I
gotta know...
- What did he tell you?
- He...
He just said they all made
a deal with you.
Oh. Hmm.
He told you about that, huh?
The deal.
He said
you gave some information
on some drops thing,
and that's how
he became mayor.
He said you were
a very important man.
Right.
Mm-hmm.
Hmm. Okay.
Just take it easy.
Jesus, he's strangling her.
Take it easy.
Rata Alada.
A falcon has wings, too.
Falcone is the rat?
Falcone works for you guys?
The mayor? The DA?
No.
We work for him.
Everybody does.
How?
Through Renewal.
Renewal is everything.
- The Renewal Fund?
- Yeah.
After Thomas Wayne died,
they all went after it
like vultures.
The mayor, Falcone, Maroni.
Everyone got in on it.
It was perfect
for making bribes,
laundering money.
A huge charitable fund
with no oversight.
Everybody got a piece.
But Falcone wanted more.
So he orchestrated a play
to take Maroni down big.
He'd rat out
his drops operation,
make the careers of everybody
that went after him,
then install them all
as his puppets.
You think this goddamn
election matters?
Falcone's the mayor.
He's been the mayor
for the last 20 years.
Come on, Vengeance.
Let's go kill
that son of a bitch.
This creep too.
Let's finish this.
-Oh, God!
-No!
We'll get him.
-But not that way.
-There is no other way!
-He owns the city!
-Cross that line,
you'll become just like him.
Listen to me.
Don't throw your life away.
Don't worry, honey.
I got nine of 'em.
No, don't! Hey, hey!
Oh, God!
She won't
get out of there alive.
And if she kills Falcone,
we may never find the Riddler.
-I have to stop her.
-Don't you mean "we"?
I gotta do this my way.
And then what?
We do what Riddler said.
Bring the rat into the light.
Can you tell Mr. Falcone
I'd like to come up?
He ain't seein' nobody
tonight.
Tell him it's about Annika.
Hey!
Look who it is, huh?
-Sorry to bother you.
-Nah. It's fine, beautiful.
I was just hoping I could
talk to you for a minute?
Absolutely.
Alone?
Hey!
I'm just so worried.
I... I don't know
where she is.
And I know that
you're a very important man.
I was hoping that maybe
you could help me find her...
because she's been gone
so long, I'm beginning to...
- I'm sorry.
- It's okay.
-I'm so sorry.
-I understand. Here.
No, that's okay,
I have a tissue.
-Mr. Falcone?
-Vinnie!
-Didn't I tell you?
-I'm sorry, Mr. Falcone.
I really think you're gonna
want to see this.
I'm sorry, beautiful.
I'll be right back.
Holy shit.
That recording,
provided to GC-1
by Lieutenant James Gordon
of the Gotham PD.
And we should warn you,
the contents
are extremely graphic,
and some of you
may find it disturbing.
He just said
they all made a deal with you.
Oh. Hmm.
He told you
about that, huh?
The deal.
He said
you gave some information
on some drops thing,
and that's how
he became mayor.
He said you were
a very important man.
Right.
Hmm. Okay.
Revelations
of Mr. Falcone's secret role
as a mafia informant...
Hey, Dad.
What?
I'm Maria Kyle's kid.
You remember her?
Yeah.
Just...
Just put down the gun, honey.
This is for my mother.
I see him!
You don't think this hurts me?
My own flesh and blood, huh?
You made me do this.
Just like your mother.
He has to pay!
You don't have to pay
with him.
You paid enough.
Jesus.
Look at you, man.
What do you think this is?
You think
you're gonna scare me
with that mask and that cape?
I'm gonna start crying,
and all of a sudden,
some big secret's comin' out?
Let me tell you something.
Whatever I know,
whatever I've done,
it's all going with me
to my grave.
What, are you with Zorro
over here?
Don't you know you boys
in blue work for me?
I guess
we don't all work for you.
You have the right
to remain silent.
Anything you say can
and will be used against you
in a court of law.
You have the right
to an attorney.
If you cannot afford one,
the City of Gotham
will provide one to you.
Do you understand
these rights?
Do you understand?
Yeah.
I'll see you when I walk out.
With these rights in mind,
is there anything else
you wish to tell...
Goddamn rat.
What'd you say?
Enjoy your night
at Blackgate, Carmine.
Probably be your last.
Oh-ho! So you're
a big man now, Oz, huh?
Maybe I am.
Really, Oz?
Because to me, you were always
just a gimp in an empty suit.
I'll spray paint your ass!
What are you doing?
It wasn't me!
I didn't shoot!
Get your hands off of me!
"Bring him into the light.
And you'll find
where I'm at."
There!
The shots came from up there!
It's Riddler.
Gage, on me.
Martinez, around back.
Nobody gets in there,
nobody gets out!
He's gone.
He's been here
this whole time.
-Lieutenant. Martinez.
-Yeah?
Lieutenant,
we got a witness here,
says she saw someone
coming down
the fire escape
right after the shot.
She said he went
into the corner diner.
The guy's sitting by himself
at the counter, right now.
Police! Hands up!
He said put
your goddamn hands up,
you son of a bitch.
I just ordered
a slice of pumpkin pie.
Stay still!
Now!
Which one is you?
You tell me.
Let's go, pencil-neck.
Get that son of a bitch
out of here!
...where
even murdered mayor
Don Mitchell, Jr.'s wife
and son
have gathered in an emotional
show of city unity.
Our Dan O'Neil is live
inside Real's headquarters
right now...
Hey.
What are all these diaries?
They're ledgers.
He's got thousands.
He scrawled all over 'em.
Rambling, ciphers, codes.
Got something back
on one of the IDs.
Edward Nashton. Works at KTMJ.
-He's a forensic accountant.
-Accountant?
Hey, Lieutenant!
You really okay with this?
What about chain of evidence?
You should see this.
He's wearing gloves.
"Friday, July 16th.
My life has been a cruel
riddle I could not solve,
suffocating my mind,
no escape.
But then, today, I saw it.
A single word on this ledger,
sitting on the desk beside me.
'Renewal.'
The empty promise
they sold to me
as a child in that orphanage.
One look inside,
and finally I understood.
My whole life has been
preparing me for this.
The moment
when I would learn the truth.
When I could finally
strike back
and expose their lies."
"If you want people to
understand, really understand,
you can't just
give them the answers.
You have to confront them,
torture them
with the horrifying questions,
just like they tortured me.
I know now
what I must become."
Jesus.
I don't think that rat
likes you, man.
This one's not a rat.
What is that?
Some kind of pry tool?
Is it a chisel?
It's a murder weapon.
He killed Mitchell with it.
The edge will match
the floorboard impression
in the mayor's study.
"My confession"?
What's he confessing to?
He already told us
he killed Mitchell.
This isn't over.
Oh, man.
He's been posting
all kinds of shit online.
He's got, like, 500 followers.
Real fringe types.
His final post was last night.
Some video.
Got a lot of views,
but it's password-protected.
Can you get in?
Copying his drive now.
Take some time,
but we'll get in.
- Show me the post.
- It's right here.
"The Truth Unmasked."
I think I'm his last target.
You?
Maybe this is all
coming to an end.
What is?
The Batman.
Yeah?
Right.
Riddler's asking for you.
At Arkham.
You're a good cop.
I told you
I'd see you in hell.
What do you
want from me?
"Want"?
If only you knew how long
I've been waiting
for this day.
For this moment.
I've been invisible
my whole life.
I guess I won't be anymore,
will I?
They'll remember me now.
They'll remember
both of us.
Bruce...
Wayne.
You know,
I was there that day.
The day the great Thomas Wayne
announced
he was running for mayor,
made all those promises.
Well, a week later
he was dead,
and everybody
just forgot about us.
All they could talk about
was poor Bruce Wayne.
Bruce Wayne, the orphan.
Orphan.
Living in some tower
over the park
isn't being an orphan.
Looking down on everyone,
with all that money.
Don't you tell me.
Do you know
what being an orphan is?
It's 30 kids to a room.
Twelve years old
and already a drophead,
numbing the pain.
You wake up screaming
with rats
chewing your fingers.
And every winter
one of the babies die
because it's so cold.
But, oh, no.
Let's talk
about the billionaire
with the lying,
dead daddy,
because at least the money
makes it go down easy.
Doesn't it?
Bruce...
Wayne.
He's the only one
we didn't get.
But we got the rest of 'em,
didn't we?
All those slick,
sleazy, phony pricks.
God.
Look at you.
Your mask is amazing.
I wish you could've
seen me in mine.
Ain't it funny?
All everyone wants to do
is unmask you,
but they're missing the point.
You and I both know,
I'm looking at the real you
right now.
My mask allowed me
to be myself,
completely.
No shame,
no limits.
Why did you write me?
What do you mean?
All those cards.
I told you,
we've been
doing this together.
You're a part of this.
We didn't do
anything together.
We did.
What did we just do?
I asked you to bring him
into the light, and you did.
We're such a good team.
We're not a team.
I never could have gotten him
out of there.
I'm not physical.
My strength is up here.
I mean, I had all the pieces,
I had the answers.
But I didn't know
how to make them listen.
You gave me that.
I gave you nothing.
You showed me
what was possible.
all it takes is fear
and a little focused violence.
You inspired me.
You're out
of your goddamn mind.
What?
This is all in your head.
You're sick, twisted.
How can you say that?
You think
you'll be remembered?
You're a pathetic
psychopath,
-begging for attention.
-No.
You're gonna die alone
in Arkham.
-No. No, no, no!
-A nobody!
No!
Ahhh!
This is not how
this was supposed to go!
Ahhh!
I had it all planned out!
We were gonna
be safe here.
We could watch
the whole thing together.
Watch what?
Everything!
It was all there.
You mean,
you didn't figure it out?
Oh, you're really not as smart
as I thought you were.
I guess I gave you
too much credit.
What have you done?
What's black and blue
and dead all over?
You.
If you think you can stop
what's coming.
What have you done?
Ave Maria
What
have you done?
Gratia plena
What have you done?
Maria
Gratia plena
Hey!
What are you doing in here?
Hey, man, I don't think that
you should be touching that.
Boy, this guy's
a real nutjob, huh?
Killing Mitchell
with a friggin' carpet tool.
My uncle's a...
He's an installer.
You know, it's a...
Oh, you know.
It's a... a tucker.
Huh.
Hey, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa!
What are you doing?
Hey, guys.
Uh, thanks
for all the comments,
and, uh, a special thanks
to everyone
for the tips
on detonators.
Detonators?
I just want to say
this will be
my last postfor a
little while, and, uh...
what this community
has meant to me
these weeks,
these months,
let's just say
none of us...
is alone anymore. Okay?
Jesus.
Tomorrow's Election Day.
And Bella Real will win.
She promised real change.
But we know the truth,
don't we?
You've seen
Gotham's true face now.
Together, we've
unmasked it.
Its corruption, its perversion
masquerading
under the guise of renewal.
But unmasking
is not enough.
The day of judgment
is finally upon us.
And now it is time
for retribution.
I've parked seven vans
all along the
city seawall.
And on the big night,
they
will go boom.
Boom!
When the vans blow,
the flooding
will happen so fast,
evacuation
will not be an option.
Those who are not
washed away
will race through the streets
in terror.
Call Gordon.
Yeah. Yeah, yeah. Yeah.
As breaking news
hits higher ground
in Gotham Square Garden,
celebrations
will turn to panic,
as the venue becomes
the city's shelter
of last resort.
And that's where
all of you come in.
Now, when the time arrives,
I will already be unmasked.
The pigs will have me
in their custody,
but that's okay.
Because then
it will be your turn.
You'll be there, waiting.
It's time for the lies
to finally end.
False
promises of renewal?
Change?
We'll give them real,
real change now.
We've spent our lives
in this wretched place,
suffering!
Wondering, "Why us?"
Now they will spend their
last moments wondering,
why them?
I can't get through!
The lines are down.
Hey, hey, hey! Road's closed!
I'm just trying
to get out of town, man!
Lady, we got bombs going off.
The whole city's flooding.
You're gonna have to go
inside the Garden
with everyone else.
-Lieutenant, who's in charge?
-I really don't know.
We're just trying
to get a handle here, sir.
Right. Hey, listen! Quiet!
We got an active situation.
We need to sweep the building
for explosives
and get the mayor-elect out
of here, now. Where is she?
-I can take you there.
-Come!
If we don't close
the doors, we're gonna have...
-MCU.
-...huge problems.
The water's
already started to breach.
I thought this was a shelter
of last resort.
Yeah, for a hurricane,
but not if the whole seawall
comes down.
I am not gonna let
those people die out there.
All right.
I'll go calm down the crowd
-so we can get everyone in.
-It's not safe for you here.
We need to get you out,
Ms. Real.
-I'm not going anywhere.
-We're under attack, ma'am.
Exactly! That's the problem
with this city.
Everyone's afraid to stand up
and do the right thing,
but I'm not.
-Excuse me.
-Ma'am...
Everyone, everyone,
if I could just
get your attention.
Please!
I just need your attention!
You're okay!
Hey! Hey!
How do I get up there?
Follow me, sir.
No, no. It's okay.
It's okay.
It's done now. It's done.
It's over.
Hey!
Hey! Hey, man, take it easy!
Take it easy.
Easy.
Jesus.
Who the hell are you?
Me?
I'm Vengeance.
Wednesday,
November 6th.
The city is underwater.
The National
Guard is coming.
Martial law is in effect,
but the criminal element
never sleeps.
Looting and lawlessness
will be rampant
in the parts of the city
no one can get to.
I can already see
things will get worse
before they get better.
And some will seize the chance
to grab everything they can.
We will rebuild.
But not just our city.
We must rebuild people's faith
in our institutions,
in our elected officials,
in each other.
Together, we will learn
to believe in Gotham again.
I'm starting
to see now.
I have had an
effect here...
but not the
one I intended.
Vengeance
won't change the past,
mine or anyone else's.
I have to become more.
People need hope.
To know someone's
out there for them.
The city's angry,
scarred,
like me.
Our scars can destroy us.
Even after the physical wounds
have healed.
But if we survive them,
they can transform us.
They can give
us the power
to endure...
and the strength
to fight.
We are live.
As you can see,
the masked vigilante
atop Gotham Square Garden,
helping to save the lives
of hundreds of victims.
And now as
first responders
desperately scramble
to help the injured,
a mysterious masked man
emerges,
heroically pulling the
victimsright through that skylight...
Isn't that just terrible?
Him...
raining on your parade
like that?
What is it they say?
"One day you're on top...
the next,
you're a clown."
Well...
let me tell you,
there are worse things to be.
Hey, hey, hey. Don't be sad.
You did so well.
And you know,
Gotham loves a comeback story.
Who are you?
Well,
that's the question,
isn't it?
Riddle me this...
"The less of them you have,
the more one is worth."
A friend.
You're leaving.
Jesus.
Don't you ever just say hello?
Where will you go?
I don't know. Upstate.
Bludhaven, maybe.
Why?
You asking me to stay?
You know this place
is never gonna change.
With Carmine gone, it's only
gonna get worse for you.
There's gonna be a power grab.
It'll be bloody.
I know.
But the city can change.
It won't.
I have to try.
It's gonna kill you
eventually. You know that.
Listen.
Why don't you come with me?
Get into some trouble.
Knock off some
CEO hedge fund types.
It'll be fun.
The bat and the cat.
It's got a nice ring.
Who am I kidding?
You're already spoken for.
You should go.
Selina...
Take care of yourself.